

YONG LIN WANG

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CO-OP STUDENT | YONGLINWANG.CA

SKILLS

Experienced in making websites and web applications using HTML, CSS, and Javascript.

Developed **UI Component Kits.** Understands good UX
design standards and familiar
with UI design tools.

Implemented and adapted common javascript libraries for front-end development

Built and tested software products in **Python**.

Written and tested code in **Java** for school.

Experienced in team management tools like Slack and Trello.

Skilled in English writing, and communication. Fluent in English and Mandarin speaking.

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE DEVELOPER • 2014 - 2017

- Developed active listening skills through hearing client requests and built applications according to specifications provided by the clients.
- Involved with Front-end application design and development in HTML 5 with JavaScript and CSS3. Engaged in creating responsive, mobile first graphic design and web-layouts for a diverse range of screen sizes.
- Engaged in Back-end server-application design, development, and monitoring with PHP and mySQL.
- Handled hosting service administration with direct admin applications like cPanel, phpMyAdmin and FTP clients.
- Prepared a variety of quotations for clients' unique needs with Microsoft Office Suite.
- Provided graphic designing service (Posters, Logos, etc.) using Photoshop, Illustrator, and inDesign.

CO-FOUNDER, FULL STACK DEV • SCHOOL DOT LIFE INC. • OCT 2016 – MAY 2018

- Built, tested, and deployed scalable software product in Node.js to streamline information management workflow
- Made presentations to school board officials, school administrators, teachers, parents, and students to pitch the information platform.
- Responsible for spearheading the team at software prototyping and development cycle of the company's main product.
- Implemented dynamic and responsive customer-oriented application using Meteor.js and Blaze reaching over 1000 users in my home high school.
- Implemented private and public APIs consumed by the company's internal systems and web/mobile clients for the customers using Meteor.js.
- Implemented various libraries to abstract common code in both the front-end and the back-end of the application

- Established Continuous Integration (CI) and source control using GitHub.
- Integrated third-party (Google) login with OAuth.
- Built infrastructure that allows images uploaded to the website be stored on AWS S3 and be fetched from the same location.
- Designed build and deployment infrastructure for company's main application on Heroku.

More about this project: http://schooldotlife.com/ Codebase: https://github.com/callmekungfu/school.life

EDUCATION

OSSD • 2014-2018 • UNIONVILLE HIGH SCHOOL

3-year honor roll recipient. Received international business subject award. Organized school robotics club. Participated in the school ultimate frisbee team and track and field team.

BASC • 2018-NOW • UNIVERSITY OF OTTAWA

Currently studying software engineering at University of Ottawa as a co-op student.

PROJECTS + RECOGNITIONS

MARKHAM HONEY HOUSE RENOVATION. MAY 2017.

This project was initiated by Markham Museum and Unionville High School, as the student leader of this project. I was responsible for overseeing the creation of materials as well as the technical development of the interactive components. More about this project can be seen here:

https://www.markham.ca/wps/portal/Markham/AboutMarkham/ NewsRoom/NewsReleases/markham-museum-opens-newlyrenovated-honey-house-at-international-museum-day-celebrations

HONORS

Ontario Skills Challenge – IT Administration Skills Bronze Medalist Ontario Skills Challenge – Website Development Bronze Medalist Ontario Skills Challenge – Website Development Silver Medalist